sapphiretech.com 2011-12-29

# Sapphire Technology Web Site

**SAPPHIRE Privacy and Web Site Usage Policy**

Welcome to Sapphiretech.com. This Web site is owned and operated by SAPPHIRE TECHNOLOGY LTD., operating under the names SAPPHIRE and SAPPHIRE TECHNOLOGY LTD. (collectively referred to throughout this document and Web site as “SAPPHIRE”).

SAPPHIRE may collect information from customers and others using our Web site (collectively referred to as “Users”). We are firmly committed to protecting the privacy, confidentiality, accuracy and security of Users’ personal information. Personal information includes any factual or subjective information, recorded or not, about an identifiable individual. This includes information in any form. Personal information does not include aggregated information that cannot be associated with a specific individual or the name, title, business address or telephone number of an employee of an organization.

* * *

**Principle 1 – Accountability**

> SAPPHIRE is accountable for the protection of all personal information within the organization's possession or control, including any personal information that has been transferred to a third party for any purposes.  We will not sell, trade or rent any of our Users’ personal information to any third parties without the consent of the User.

**Principle 2 - Identifying purposes**

> The purpose(s) for collecting any information from our Users will be identified before the information is collected.   In general, SAPPHIRE collects personal information only for the following purposes:
> 
>   * To provide requested information.
>   * To establish and maintain responsible commercial relations with customers to provide ongoing service.
>   * To understand customer needs and preferences. For example, to maintain a record of the SAPPHIRE products you have purchased in the past.
>   * For the administration of contests.
>   * To meet legal and regulatory requirements. For example, SAPPHIRE may collect personal information from you to satisfy government regulations.
> 

> 
> Additional purposes for collecting personal information may be identified to an individual before or at the time of collection.
> 
> If you would like to be added to or removed from our e-mail list, you can email us at [privacy@sapphiretech.com](mailto:privacy@sapphiretech.com)

**Principle 3 – Consent**

> SAPPHIRE requests permission to use information collected for a number of business development purposes.  Personal information such as name, address and email address is collected on a voluntary basis. 
> 
> SAPPHIRE will obtain consent before or when it collects, uses or discloses personal information about an individual.  An individual can provide consent to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information about them expressly or implicitly.  For example, completion of the optional online contact form implies consent for the purposes of providing information on our products and services.
> 
> Only Users who are not minors should provide personal information.  By providing personal information, the User is representing that the User is not a minor.

**Principle 4 - Limiting Collection**

> Any personal information we collect from Users will be limited to only those details necessary for the identified purpose. We will not collect more information than we need to fulfill the purpose identified to Users.

**Principle 5 - Limiting Use, Disclosure, and Retention**

> Users’ personal information will not be used or disclosed for purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with consent or as required by law. We will keep a User's personal information only for as long as necessary to fulfill the purpose identified to the User.

**Principle 6 – Accuracy**

> We will keep our Users’ personal information as accurate, complete and up-to-date as is necessary for the purposes for which it is to be used.  We provide you with the opportunity to update personal information you have provided.  If you require changes to previously provided personal information, please contact us at [privacy@sapphiretech.com](mailto:privacy@sapphiretech.com)

**Principle 7 – Safeguards**

> Users’ personal information shall be protected with security measures that are appropriate for the sensitivity level of the information.
> 
> Our employees are required to comply with our Information Security Policy as mentioned above. In addition, all employees are required to abide by the privacy standards we have established. Unauthorized access to and/or disclosure of User personal information by an employee of SAPPHIRE is strictly prohibited.

**Principle 8 – Openness**

> We will provide and make readily available to Users, information on our policies, procedures and practices relating to how Users’ personal information is managed.

**Principle 9 - User Access**

> Upon request, a User will be informed of the existence, use, and disclosure of his or her personal information and will be given access to that information. A User may verify the accuracy and completeness of the information and have it amended as appropriate.  If your require access to your previously provided personal information, please contact [privacy@sapphiretech.com](mailto:privacy@sapphiretech.com)

**Principle 10 – Compliance**

> A User may forward any questions or enquiries about compliance with these privacy principles to our Privacy Officer.

GENERAL WEB SITE POLICIES ****

**Automatic Data Collection**

> SAPPHIRE collects information about the a) type of browser used, b) date and time of each visit, and c) internet protocol address of the locations to which each visitor linked for each visit made to our Web Site. This information is for statistical reporting purposes only. SAPPHIRE makes no attempt to link these Internet protocol addresses with the identity of individuals visiting the Web Site.

**Cookies**

> When you access the SAPPHIRE Web site, a “cookie” may be automatically installed on your hard-drive. A cookie is a small text file that contains a unique identification number, which can be used to identify your browser, but not you. Cookies form an essential part of the Internet today by allowing servers to recognize Users’ browsers when the Users return to previously visited Web sites.  Since cookies are only text files, they cannot "run" on your computer and have no ability to search your computer for information or to transmit information to anyone. Although cookies may help enrich your Internet experience, you are free to prevent the installation of cookies on your hard-drive, including the SAPPHIRE cookie, by simply disabling the feature in your browser's options.

**External Links**

> This web site, or other SAPPHIRE’ materials, may contain links to other sites.  SAPPHIRE is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other Web sites. The terms and conditions of the SAPPHIRE’ privacy policy do not apply to any such linked Web sites. SAPPHIRE does not endorse any linked Web sites, or the information, materials, products or services that are contained in or accessible through such linked Web sites. SAPPHIRE disclaims all warranties, express or implied, with respect to the information, materials, products and services that are contained in or accessible through linked Web sites, including, but not limited to, implied warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose or non-infringement.

**Opt-Out Policy**

> To remove your information from our database or marketing lists, so as not to receive any future communications or offers of services you can email us at:  
>  >Technical or Customer Support: [eutech@sapphiretech.com](mailto:eutech@sapphiretech.com)  
>  >SAPPHIRE Select Club: [sscadmin@sapphiretech.com](mailto:sscadmin@sapphiretech.com)

**Privacy Questions & Concerns**

> If you have any questions or concerns about our personal information handling practices, please contact our Privacy Officer: [privacy@sapphiretech.com ](mailto:privacy@sapphiretech.com)

**Policy Updates**

> SAPPHIRE reserves the right to change or modify this privacy policy and our information handling practices. A modification date will be posted.

* * *

Updated as of Wednesday, March 10, 2010
